Guide to the Frederick W. Hilles Manuscript Collection and Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Frederick W. Hilles Manuscript Collection, 1645–1969; Series I; 17.94; 41 boxes + 1 broadside.
  - Literary and Historical Manuscripts, 1688–1951
    - Robinson, Sir William, 1784 May 22 (Box 16, Folder 442)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Elizabeth Montagu, from Bath, 3 pages.
    - Rodney, George Brydges, 1st Baron Rodney, 1769 November 19 (Box 16, Folder 443)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Dr. Ogle, from Greenwich, 2 pages.
    - Rogers, S., undated (Box 16, Folder 444)
      Autograph manuscript poem, signed, " Addressd to The Duchess of St. Alban; on the death of her Sister Mrs. Duffe ," twelve lines, 1 page.
    - Rogers, Samuel, undated (Box 16, Folder 445)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Cautley, from London, 1 page.
    - Rogers, Samuel, 1812 August 30 (Box 16, Folder 446)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Henry Rogers, from Lowther, 4 pages.
    - Rogers, Samuel, undated (Box 16, Folder 447)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Richard Brinsley Sheridan, from London, 1 page.
    - Rogers, Samuel, 1840 June 22; undated (Box 16, Folder 448)
      Two autograph letters, signed, an unidentified recipient, possibly Richard Brinsley Sheridan.
    - Roscoe, William, undated (Box 16, Folder 449)
      Two autograph letters, signed, to William Stanley Roscoe and an unidentified recipient. Accompanied by an engraving of Roscoe's birthplace; two copies of a portrait of Roscoe engraved by S. Freeman from the painting by J. Lonsdale; and two variant copies of Alfred Croquis' etching of Roscoe.
    - Ruskin, John, 1851 October 16 (Box 16, Folder 450)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Sir Charles Lock Eastlake, from Venice, 2 pages.
    - Ruskin, John, 1871 June 24 (Box 16, Folder 451)
    - Russell, John, Duke of Bedford, ? February 3 (Box 16, Folder 452)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Richard Brinsley Sheridan, from Bedford, 2 pages.
    - St. John, Mary (Gwatkin), 1860 March 11 (Box 16, Folder 453)
      Autograph letter, written in the third person, to Sir John Bowring, from Torquay, 3 pages. With a copy by Frederick W. Hilles of a leaf from a notebook Sir Joshua Reynolds kept on a trip to Antwerp in July 1785; the original leaf was presented to the Royal Academy in 1936 by Frederick W. Hilles.
    - Scotland, National Monument Committee, undated (Box 16, Folder 454)
      Printed letter, completed in manuscript, pertaining to the subscription for the National Monument of Scotland. Addressed to Arthur Murray of Broughton and signed by Walter Scott and other members of the Committee.
    - Scott, Lady (Charlotte Carpentier), 1854 June 24?; 1854 June 24 (Box 16, Folder 455)
      Autograph letter, written in the third person, to an unidentified recipient, 1 page.
    - Scott, W., 1841? October 30; 1841 October 30 (Box 16, Folder 456)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Robert Cadell, from St. Boswells, 3 pages.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, circa 1825-1830; 1804–1835 (Box 42, Folder 937)
      A collection of manuscripts and letters by or relating to Sir Walter, including:
      1. Scott, Sir Walter. "Upon the Ancient History of Scotland": autograph manuscript draft of a portion of the history, circa 1825-1830.
      2. Unidentified. "Universal History": autograph manuscript draft of chapters I-VII. 1804 April 29.
      3. Scott, Sir Walter. Unidentified autograph manuscript, circa 1816.
      4. Scott, Sir Walter. "Singular adventure of an odd arm case...": autograph manuscript, circa 1829.
      5. Scott, Sir Walter. 5 letters (copies in an unidentified hand) to Capt. Basil Hall: 1825 June 15, Edinburgh; 1825 October 13, Abbotsford; 1827 February 26; 1827 April 1?; 1829 September 23, Abbotsford. With notes by Basil Hall. In brown paper covers with signature of J. G. Lockhart on the front cover.
      6. Scott, Sir Walter. "Trials and other proceedings in matters criminal before the High Court of Justiciary in Scotland...": manuscript review of Pitcairn's work, with autograph corrections and additions by Scott, circa 1829.
      7. Unidentified. The illness of King George III: manuscript copy of notes, circa 1835.
      8. Unidentified. Manuscript notes on Ireland, circa 1824.
      9. Cockburn, Sir George. "Extract from the diary of Rear Admiral Sir George Cockburn with particular reference to General Napoleon Buonaparte...": manuscript copy in an unidentified hand, circa 1815.
      10. Cockburn, Sir George? Memoirs of Napoleon Buonaparte: manuscript notes in an unidentified hand, circa 1815 July 31.
      11. Cockburn, Sir George? Description of Napoleon Buonaparte: manuscript notes in an unidentified hand, circa 1815 July 31.
      12. Scott, Sir Walter. "Tales of My Landlord": proofs of the Introduction with autograph corrections by Scott, circa 1830.
      13. Unidentified. "Quentin Durwood": manuscript notes on Quentin Durward, circa 1835.
      14. "List of Sir Walter Scott's Writings": manuscript in an unidentified hand, undated. With autograph manuscript note by Sir Walter Scott listing six of his writings.
      Bound together in quarter brown leather and paper boards, labelled on front cover "Scott Papers Reviews etc."
    - Scott, Sir Walter, undated (Box 16, Folder 457)
      Proof sheet of pages 67-68 of History of Scotland, with autographmanuscript corrections and annotations by the author, 1 leaf.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, circa 1806; 1801–1811 (Box 36, Folder 921)
      Autograph manuscript notebook, bound in brown leather, with brass clasp intact.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, undated (Box 16, Folder 458)
      Proof sheets of pages vii - xviii of Rob Roy, with autograph manuscript corrections and annotations by the author, 6 leaves.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, 1817–1820 (Box 16, Folder 459)
      Four autograph letters, signed, to James Ballantyne.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, ? May 29 (Box 17, Folder 460)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Sir George Beaumont, from Edinburgh, 1 page.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, 1811 August 9 (Box 17, Folder 461)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from Ashestiel, 1 page.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, 1823 April 28 (Box 17, Folder 462)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, possibly Atkinson, from Abbotsford, 2 pages.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, 1816 February 19; 1816 February 16 (Box 17, Folder 463)
      Autograph letter, signed, to John Wilson Croker, 3 pages.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, 1819 August 1 (Box 17, Folder 464)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Hay Donaldson, from Abbotsford, 1 page.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, 1822 November 12 (Box 17, Folder 465)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Maria Edgeworth, from Abbotsford, 2 pages. Includes a note from Miss Edgeworth to Miss Griffith at the head of page 1.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, 1806 July 31 (Box 17, Folder 466)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Anne Ellis, from Edinburgh, 1 page.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, 1827 October 4 (Box 17, Folder 467)
      Two autograph letters, signed, to Sir Francis Freeling.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, 1826 April 28 (Box 17, Folder 468)
      Autograph letter, signed, to John Gibson, 2 pages.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, 1829 November 1 (Box 17, Folder 469)
      Autograph letter, signed, to John Gibson, from Abbotsford, 2 pages.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, 1826 June 13 (Box 17, Folder 470)
      Autograph letter, signed, to G. Handley, from Edinburgh, 2 pages. Accompanied by an engraving of Scott by G. J. Anderton from the portrait by C. R. Leslie.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, 1829 May 18 (Box 17, Folder 471)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Andrew Lang, 1 page.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, 1829 February 10 (Box 17, Folder 472)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Colin Mackenzie, 3 pages.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, 1819 July 8 (Box 17, Folder 473)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Miss Millar, from Abbotsford, 2 pages.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, 1824 November 30 (Box 17, Folder 474)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Hugh Percy, Third Duke of Northumberland, from Edinburgh, 1 page.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, 1808–1829 (Box 17, Folder 475)
      Eight autograph letters to Richard Polwhele. Some letters include manuscript copies of verses. Accompanied by a copy of a dispensation to John Froward, possibly sent from Polwhele to Scott.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, 1829 December 9 (Box 17, Folder 476)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Pringle, from Edinburgh, 2 pages. Accompanied by a manuscript copy of the letter in an unidentified hand.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, 1821 February 2 (Box 17, Folder 477)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Sir William Rae, from Edinburgh, 2 pages.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, 1826? January 23; 1826 January 23 (Box 17, Folder 478)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Henry Raeburn, from Edinburgh, 1 page.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, 1816 March 11 (Box 17, Folder 479)
      Autograph letter, signed, to John Scott, from Abbotsford, 2 pages.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, 1819 December 17 (Box 17, Folder 480)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Scott, from Edinburgh, 2 pages. Accompanied by a reproduction of an engraved portrait of Scott.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, 1828 April 1 (Box 17, Folder 481)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Sir Cuthbert Sharpe, from Abbotsford, 2 pages.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, 1820 April 1 (Box 17, Folder 482)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, possibly Mr. Sherwell, from London, 1 page.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, 1809 (Box 17, Folder 483)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Marianne Waddington, from Edinburgh, 4 pages.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, 1825 January 5 (Box 17, Folder 484)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Arthur Wellesley, First Duke of Wellington, from Abbotsford, 2 pages.
    - Scott, Sir Walter, 1822 August 27 (Box 17, Folder 485)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Edward Booth Wilbraham, from Edinburgh, 2 pages.
    - Scott, Sir William, 1810 (Box 17, Folder 486)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Lady Frances (Wilton) Chambers, from Reading, 2 pages. On the verso of the envelope is an autograph manuscript note, possibly from Chambers.
    - Shee, Martin Archer, 1824 August 14 (Box 17, Folder 487)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Charles Parr Burney, from London, 2 pages.
    - Shee, Martin Archer, 1830 April 9 (Box 17, Folder 488)
    - Sheridan, G., undated (Box 17, Folder 489)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from Leicester House, 3 pages.
    - Sheridan, Richard Brinsley, 1770 October 13?; 1770 October 13 (Box 17, Folder 490)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Elizabeth (Johnson) Angelo, from Bath, 3 pages.
    - Sheridan, Richard Brinsley, 1811-1812?; 1811–1812 (Box 17, Folder 491)
      Autograph letter, signed with initials, to Richard Peake, from London, 1 page.
    - Shirley, L., 1877 March 2 (Box 17, Folder 492)
    - Siddons, Sarah, 1818 May 18 (Box 17, Folder 493)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Hester Lynch Thrale Piozzi, from London, 2 pages.
    - Sigourney, Lydia H., 1842 December 6 (Box 17, Folder 494)
      Autograph letter, signed, to the Reverend L. Woods, from Boston, 2 pages.
    - Simeon, Charles, 1818 October 28 (Box 17, Folder 495)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Atkinson, from Cambridge, 3 pages.
    - Sinclair, Sir John, undated (Box 17, Folder 496)
      Two autograph letters, signed, to Richard Brinsley Sheridan.
    - Smith, Robert Payne, 1878 October 2 (Box 17, Folder 497)
      Autograph letter, signed, to M. Martin, from Canterbury, 1 page.
    - Smollett, Tobias, 1757 November 5 (Box 17, Folder 498)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from Chelsea, 1 page. In a tan calf gilt volume with two engravings of Smollett.
    - Smythe, Sir Sidney Stafford, circa 1774?; 1769–1779 (Box 17, Folder 499)
      Autograph letter to William Murray, First Earl of Mansfield, 1 page.
    - Snee, Edward L., 1818 December 4 (Box 17, Folder 500)
    - Sookmay, Moha Rajah, 1805–1806 (Box 17, Folder 501)
      Two letters, signed, in the hand of an amanuensis, to Lady Frances (Wilton) Chambers, from Calcutta.
    - Sotheby, William, undated (Box 17, Folder 502)
      Autograph presentation inscription to Christopher Anstey.
    - Soulburn, E. M.?, 1884 October 7 (Box 17, Folder 503)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. Nisbet, from London, 1 page.
    - Spencer, George John, Second Earl Spencer, 1818 December 8 (Box 17, Folder 504)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Sir Samuel Edgerton Brydges, from Althorp, 1 page.
    - Stanhope, Philip Dormer, Fourth Earl of Chesterfield, 1740 August 3 (Box 17, Folder 505)
      Autograph letter to Philip Stanhope, from Tunbridge, 2 pages.
    - Stanhope, Philip Dormer, Fourth Earl of Chesterfield, 1733–1750 (Box 17, Folder 506)
      Nine autograph letters, signed, to Arthur Villettes.
    - Stanley, Lady Dorothy, undated (Box 17, Folder 507)
      Two autograph letters, signed, to a "Lady Catherine."
    - Sterne, Laurence, 1760 June 19 (Box 18, Folder 508)
      Fragment of an autograph letter, signed, to William Warburton, from Coxwold, 4 pages. Pages 1 and 2 and portions of pages 3 and 4 are supplied in manuscript in an unidentified hand.
    - Steuben, ?, 1791 January 22 (Box 18, Folder 509)
      A bill of exchange, partly printed, authorizing the payment of $225.00 to R. Troopages New York. Signed "Steuben."
    - Stevens, E., 1809 March (Box 18, Folder 510)
      Two autograph letters, signed, to Henry Wagner.
    - Stockdale, Percival, 1784–1785 (Box 18, Folder 511)
      6 autograph letters, signed, to John Davidson.
    - Stowell, Hugh, 1847 August 24 (Box 18, Folder 512)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, 3 pages.
    - Strachey, Lytton, 1921 April 18 (Box 18, Folder 513)
      Autograph letter, signed, to A. C.? Pearson, from London, 2 pages.
    - Sutton, Eleanor, 1786 April 20 (Box 18, Folder 514)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Henry Addington, First Viscount Sidmouth, 3 pages.
    - Swinburne, Algernon Charles, 1879 July 1 (Box 18, Folder 515)
      Autograph letter, signed, to William Black, from Holmwood, 7 pages. Accompanied by a note from Cecil Lang to FWH.
    - Tarleton, P. S., circa 1802; 1797–1807 (Box 18, Folder 516)
    - Taylor, Tom, 1868 February 20 (Box 18, Folder 517)
    - Taylor, Tom, 1868 April 23 (Box 18, Folder 518)
    - Taylor, Tom, 1883 December 9 (Box 18, Folder 519)
      Autograph letter, written in the third person, to Lady Seymour, from London, 3 pages.
    - Tenniel, John, 1848 (Box 18, Folder 520)
    - Tennyson, Alfred, 1st Baron Tennyson, undated (Box 18, Folder 521)
      Autograph note, signed, to his printer, 1 leaf.
    - Thackeray, Francis, 1828 October 28 (Box 18, Folder 522)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Burn, from London, 2 pages.
    - Thackeray, Francis, 1828 June 4 (Box 18, Folder 523)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Rodd, from Harpenden, 1 page.
    - Thompson, William Hepworth, 1868 May 28 (Box 18, Folder 524)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Marcus Martin, from Cambridge, 4 pages.
    - Thurlow, Edward, 1st Baron Thurlow, 1786 September 7 (Box 18, Folder 525)
      Order of August 20, 1786 to pay fifty pounds to George Augustus Selwyn. Signed by Thurlow, James Graham, Edward J. Eliot, and the Duke of Newcastle.
    - Trevelyan, George Macaulay, 1908 April 9 (Box 18, Folder 526)
      Autograph letter, signed, to "Garrett," from Palermo, 1 page.
    - Trumbull, John, 1819 January 7 (Box 18, Folder 527)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. Trumbull, Philadelphia, 1 page.
    - Trumbull, Jonathan, 1779 July 16 (Box 18, Folder 528)
      Autograph manuscript order, signed, to Brigadier General Tyler regarding the Light Infantry Company of Norwich.
    - Trumbull, Jonathan, 1781 January 31 (Box 18, Folder 529)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Nathaniel Shaw, from Hartford, 1 page.
    - Tytler, Patrick Fraser, undated (Box 18, Folder 530)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from Edinburgh, 1 page.
    - Unidentified author, 1826 October; 1873 June 10 (Box 18, Folder 531)
      1. A wrapper with the title "Female Writers and Printed Poems - Examined by B. Isted October 1826."
      2. "Female Authors" list containing the names of Mrs. Montagu, Mrs. Howe, Mrs. Fielding, Mrs. Lenox sic, Mrs. Carter, etc. 2 leaves.
      3. Envelope addressed to Mr. Henry Cahoon, from J. Bull, Dublin, 1873 June 10.
      4. Envelope addressed to Mr. Sharpe in Lincoln's Inn, possibly from Joshua Reynolds.
    - Unidentified author, 1902, undated; 1902 (Box 18, Folder 532)
      Collection of autographs, including autographs of Abraham Hayward, John Delane, George Fitzclarence, E. Westminster, and S. Londonderry. Also includes one unidentified item, with an envelope addressed to Algernon Brinsley Sheridan, 1902 May.
    - Unidentified author (Box 36, Folder 922)
      Manuscript volume of recipes, notes, and poems:
      1. Recipes of Anne Fleetwood, 1668, 40 pages.
      2. John Webb diary and notes, 1816-1830s.
      3. Printed epitaphs, clipped from various sources and pasted in, 47 pages.
      4. "Memento Mori" anagram poem to Anne Fleetwood, 1 page.
      5. "Epitaphs upon a vertuous man" poem, 1 page.
      6. "The Bible" poem, 1 page.
    - Unidentified author, circa 1819; 1819 (Box 18, Folder 533)
      Autograph manuscript note reading "From my dearest Charles Sept & Octr 1819 just before his dangerous illness at Holmpton I went to him."
    - Unidentified author, undated (Box 18, Folder 534)
      Fragment of a manuscript letter in an unidentified hand to an unidentified recipient, 2 pages. From the group of Sheridan papers.
    - Unidentified author, Easter (Box 18, Folder 535)
      Autograph letter, signed, regarding Joshua Reynolds' page proofs, in an unidentified hand to an unidentified recipient, 1 page.
    - Unidentified author, undated (Box 18, Folder 536)
      Autograph letter, signed, in an unidentified hand to "Dear Madam," 1 page.
    - Unidentified author, 1885 August 15 (Box 18, Folder 537)
      Autograph letter, signed, in an unidentified hand, to "Archdeacon," from Westminster, 2 pages.
    - Unidentified author, 1868 July 12 (Box 18, Folder 538)
      Autograph letter, signed, in an unidentified hand to Mrs. James Atlay, from Bramley near Leeds, 2 pages.
    - Unidentified author, 1809 April 19 (Box 18, Folder 539)
      Autograph letter, signed, in an unidentified hand to Mrs. Benson, from Rugby, 3 pages.
    - Unidentified author, 1869 February 26 (Box 18, Folder 540)
      Fragment of an autograph letter in an unidentified hand to Mr. Pritchett, from Amsterdam, 4 pages.
    - Unidentified author (Box 18, Folder 541)
      Autograph letter, signed, in an unidentified hand to Richard Brinsley Sheridan, from London, 4 pages.
    - Unidentified author (Box 18, Folder 542)
      " Athletics ": manuscript by an unidentified author, containing comments on sports and exercise taken from Pythagoras, Galen, Plato, Petrus Fabrus and others. 4 pages. From the group of Sheridan papers.
    - Unidentified author (Box 18, Folder 543)
      " The Genius & Writings of Cowper ": manuscript by an unidentified author, 48 pages.
    - Unidentified author, 1807 March (Box 18, Folder 544)
      Manuscript notes about John Carr in an unidentified hand extracted from Gentleman's Magazine, March 1807, page 282. Formerly laid in volume labelled on spine "Fine Arts of the English School, Letters & mems" and not included on John Britton's list.
    - Unidentified author, undated (Box 31 (Oversize), Folder 886)
      Manuscript map in an unidentified hand titled "A Delineation of the Road from Islamabad the Capital of Chittigong to the Passage over the Gr. Phenny being 49.5 English Stat. Miles actually measured."
    - Unidentified author, 1786?; 1786 (Box 18, Folder 545)
      " Johnson's Ghost - by a Lady ": manuscript in an unidentified hand, Surbiton, 4 pages.
    - Unidentified author, 1770 (Box 18, Folder 546)
      Manuscript journal of a tour through Holland and Flanders. Begins in London 1770 July 27 and ends in Brussels, probably at the end of August or the beginning of September. 55 pages, with a money conversion chart in pencil on the inside back cover.
    - Unidentified author, undated (Box 36, Folder 923)
      Commonplace book, manuscript, in an unidentified hand, containing the following sections:
      1. "History and Chronology"
      2. Unidentified poetry
      3. Characters of great men
      4. Description of Babylon
      5. "Criticism" poem
      6. Dialogue between Tiberius and Belisarius
      7. Physics, with diagrams
      8. Egypt and other ancient Eastern countries
      9. Description of various English counties
      10. Description of Switzerland
      11. Medieval European history
    - Unidentified author, 1793 (Box 18, Folder 547)
      Manuscript sermon from Samuel I, 20:3 titled " There is but a step between me, and Death ," delivered at the funeral service of William Chambers, 7 pages. Includes a manuscript note on the verso of last leaf: "Sermon preached at the Funeral of my lamented brother William Chambers. F. C." (i.e. Lady Frances Chambers)
    - Vansittart, Nicholas, undated (Box 18, Folder 548)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Richard Brinsley Sheridan, from London, 2 pages.
    - Vaughan, Charles John, 1869 March 9 (Box 18, Folder 549)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from Doncaster, 3 pages.
    - Vaughan, Charles John, 1892 February 20 (Box 18, Folder 550)
      Autograph letter, written in the third person, to an unidentified recipient, from Llandaff, Wales, 1 page.
    - Versteegh, Dirk, of Amsterdam, circa 1779; 1774–1784 (Box 37, Folder 925)
      Friendship album, Amsterdam, bound in red morocco, gilt, in a brown marbled slip case, containing the following:
      1. Colored drawing signed "V. Grandjean, 1779"
      2. Two drawings, inserted
      3. Miniature portrait of Dirk Versteegh
      4. Four drawings, executed in the album
      5. Signature of Sir Joshua Reynolds on two leaves, with quotations
      6. Other signatures and quotations
    - Vesey, Agmondesham, between 1783 and 1785?; 1783–1785 (Box 18, Folder 551)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Hannah More, 1 page.
    - Vincent, H., 1815 June 19 (Box 18, Folder 552)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Lady Frances (Wilton) Chambers, 1 page.
    - Walker, Harriet, 1826 November 30 (Box 18, Folder 553)
      Autograph letter, signed, to William Sidney Walker, 3 pages.
    - Wallace, Thomas, 1797; 1820 May 28 (Box 41, Folder 936)
      Manuscript notebook and common place book containing letters and poetry and prose passages on love, death, nature, folly, matrimony, etc., either completely or partially copied from other writings.
    - Ward, Edward Matthew, 1853 March 5 (Box 18, Folder 554)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Sir Charles Lock Eastlake, from Slough, 2 pages.
    - Warren, Robert Penn, 1951–1969 (Box 18, Folder 555)
      Five typed letters, signed, to Frederick W. Hilles. Accompanied by an invitation to the wedding of Eleanor Clark and Warren.
    - Watson, Richard, Bishop of Llandaff, 1777 July 8 (Box 18, Folder 556)
      Autograph letter, signed with initials, to Daines Barrington, 2 pages. Includes an autograph letter, signed, from Barrington to Thomas Percy on page 3.
    - Watts, G. F., 1847 October 5 (Box 18, Folder 557)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Sir Charles Lock Eastlake, 2 pages.
    - Webber, Frederick, 1827 November 26 (Box 18, Folder 558)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Lady Frances (Wilton) Chambers, Malleigaon, 3 pages.
    - Webster, Thomas, undated (Box 18, Folder 559)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Richard Redgrave, 3 pages.
    - Wellington, Lady Elizabeth Hay, undated (Box 18, Folder 560)
      Two autograph letters, signed, to Algernon Brinsley Sheridan.